"Episode 15"
"에피소드 15"
underfoot
발 밑에
Madam Meng just sent the soup.
방금 멩 부인이 수프를 보냈습니다.
She said she made this soup herself.
그녀는 이 수프를 직접 만들었다고 말했습니다.
Did he do it himself?
그 사람이 직접 한 걸까요?
It doesn't seem that way.
그렇게 보이지는 않습니다.
It's all cool.
모두 멋지다.
Take it away.
멀리 가져.
Accept it.
그것을 받아들이십시오.
Has anyone noticed that?
그걸 알아차린 사람이 있나요?
Your Majesty is not in the library.
폐하께서는 도서관에 계시지 않습니다.
Teacher, don't worry. I sent them all back.
선생님, 걱정하지 마세요. 나는 그들 모두를 다시 보냈습니다.
let's go.
갑시다.
chenzi
첸쯔
government
정부
Why do you look at me like that?
왜 나를 그렇게 보는 거죠?
You've been through a lot of hardships that seem to be in the past .
그냥 과거가 된 것 같아 당신은 많은 어려움을 겪었습니다.
What did I do when I was drunk yesterday ?
어제 술에 취해 있었을 때 내가 뭘 한거지?
You didn't do anything.
당신은 아무것도 하지 않았습니다.
He just swore while riding the carriage. Just come back.
마차를 타면서 욕을 했을 뿐이었다. 그냥 돌아와.
If the mistress is not drunk
여주인이 술에 취하지 않았다면
You probably didn't know he was going through this pain.
아마 그 사람이 이런 고통을 겪고 있는지 몰랐을 거예요.
- Jong Ye-ran, you bastard - your mistress.
- 종예란, 이 새끼야 - 네 여주인.
- Madam, stop - Master Rowe.
- 부인, 그만하세요 - 로우 마스터.
- You can't do this, sir . - I...
- 이러시면 안 됩니다, 선생님 - 저는...
- I'm such an idiot - Madam, sir...
- 저는 정말 바보예요 - 부인, 선생님...
someone in love with you
당신과 사랑에 빠진 사람
- Mistress - I hate you.
- 여주인 - 당신이 싫어요.
- Who do you think you are? - Mrs. Chao.
- 당신은 누구라고 생각하시나요? - 차오 부인.
- Do you still think I like you? - ma'am.
- 아직도 내가 당신을 좋아한다고 생각하시나요? - 부인.
If you don't come back too late
너무 늦게 돌아오지만 않으면
I probably don't care about you.
나는 아마 당신에 대해 관심이 없습니다.
Sir, ma'am, you are correct.
선생님, 부인 말이 맞습니다.
You're right, don't pay attention to him.
당신 말이 맞아요, 그 사람에게 관심을 기울이지 마세요.
You don't need to pay attention to him, ma'am.
그 사람에게 주의를 기울일 필요는 없어요, 부인.
- Are you - me or you?
- 당신은 - 나 아니면 당신?
Let me tell you, yes, that's right.
내가 말해줄게, 네, 맞아요.
- Yes, it's me. - Yes, I feel bad.
- 응, 나야 - 응, 기분이 안 좋아.
That's why I allowed you and Jong Ye-ran.
그래서 너와 종예란을 허락한 거야
stay together
함께 있어라
- I... - Don't think I'm afraid of you.
- 난... - 내가 당신을 두려워한다고 생각하지 마세요.
- Yes, ma'am. - I'll tell you.
- 네, 부인 - 말씀드릴게요
- Don't be afraid, sir - don't you dare command me.
- 두려워하지 마세요, 선생님 - 감히 나에게 명령하지 마세요.
I know, I won't order you, Mistress.
알아요, 명령하지 않겠습니다, 여주인님.
I am trying to repent.
나는 회개하려고 노력하고 있습니다.
Otherwise I might kill you.
그렇지 않으면 내가 당신을 죽일 수도 있습니다.
Madam, you are right.
부인, 당신 말이 맞아요.
me...
나...
government
정부
- I... - Madam, you can't do this.
- 저는... - 부인, 이러시면 안됩니다.
government
정부
It's too dangerous.
너무 위험해요.
I almost forgot to scold you.
나는 당신을 꾸짖는 것을 거의 잊었습니다.
you are fat
너 뚱뚱해.
Yes, it's me.
네, 나예요.
Please tell us.
알려주세요.
My life is flourishing.
내 인생은 번영하고 있습니다.
So what are you doing?
그래서 당신은 무엇을하고 있습니까?
force women to become concubines
여성들을 첩으로 만들도록 강요하다
Being such a helpless person
그렇게 무력한 사람이 되어서
You keep calling me that. “Nong Ying…” stayed all day.
당신은 나를 계속 그렇게 부르죠. "농잉..."은 하루 종일 머물렀다.
I don't want to hear any more.
더 이상 듣고 싶지 않아요.
I will no longer call you “young lady ,” ma’am.
이제 더 이상 당신을 "젊은 아가씨"라고 부르지 않겠습니다 , 부인.
I have warned you many times.
나는 여러 번 경고했습니다.
But you're still out there causing trouble for me.
그런데 당신은 여전히 ​​밖에 나가서 나에게 문제를 일으키고 있어요.
- Sir, I understand. - And you're right.
- 선생님, 이해합니다 - 그리고 당신 말이 맞아요
My brother wandered off and she did what she wanted.
형은 방황했고 그녀는 원하는 대로 했습니다.
No matter what I said, no one listened to me.
내가 무슨 말을 해도 아무도 내 말을 듣지 않았습니다.
I'm listening, ma'am.
듣고 있어요, 부인.
Who do you think you are?
당신은 누구라고 생각합니까?
I'm listening to you.
너 한테 귀 기울이고있어.
Why should I endure these things?
내가 왜 이런 일들을 견뎌야 합니까?
- Madam, don't cry - I'm responsible for everything.
- 부인, 울지 마세요 - 모든 일은 제가 책임집니다.
Then he was hit by an arrow.
그러더니 화살을 맞았다.
But everyone hates me anyway.
하지만 어쨌든 모두가 나를 싫어합니다.
That's not true. No one hates you.
그것은 사실이 아닙니다. 아무도 당신을 미워하지 않습니다.
Why is my life so difficult?
내 인생은 왜 이렇게 힘든 걸까요?
No one hates you, ma'am.
아무도 당신을 미워하지 않습니다, 부인.
- No one hates you - Why is my life so hard?
- 아무도 당신을 미워하지 않습니다 - 내 인생은 왜 이렇게 힘든가요?
Please sit down, ma'am, and don't cry.
앉으세요, 부인 울지 마세요.
Who did I curse?
내가 누구를 저주했나요?
Most of them are teachers. With Mr. Noi-Hwa
그들 대부분은 선생님입니다. 노이화 씨와 함께
Then the Confessor and Butler Hua
그렇다면 무 참회자 그리고 버틀러 후아
And under your feet too.
그리고 당신의 발 아래에도.
Has anyone else heard of this?
다른 사람이 들어 본 적이 있나요?
Madam, don't worry.
부인, 걱정하지 마세요.
When Yama Hua took him to the carriage.
Yama Hua가 그를 마차에 데려갔을 때
He started screaming.
그는 소리를 지르기 시작했습니다.
So only Yama Hua and I can hear you.
그래서 오직 Yama Hua와 나만이 당신의 말을 들을 수 있습니다.
Call Hua Rongzhou.
화룽저우(Hua Rongzhou)에 전화해 보세요.
You, mistress.
당신, 여주인.
government
정부
What happened to your face?
얼굴에 무슨 일이 일어났나요?
I accidentally got hurt.
실수로 상처를 입었어요.
Please ask during martial arts training.
무술 수련 중에 부탁드립니다.
But here, no one can compete with you.
하지만 여기서는 누구도 당신과 경쟁할 수 없습니다.
What are you doing? Does it have to be difficult?
뭐하세요? 꼭 힘들어야 하나요?
Not at all.
전혀 그렇지 않습니다.
Did I hurt you last night?
내가 어젯밤에 당신에게 상처를 주었나요?
I didn't see you hit him while we were riding in the carriage .
마차를 타고 있는 동안 나는 당신이 그를 때리는 것을 보지 못했습니다.
But I don't know what happened.
하지만 무슨 일이 일어났는지 모르겠어요.
When I went to get the carriage?
내가 마차를 가지러 갔을 때?
Let me take a look. Please take off the bandage.
좀 볼게요 붕대를 풀어주세요
I hurt myself.
나 자신을 다쳤어요.
great
좋아요
You raised your voice to the point that it startled me.
당신은 나를 놀라게 할 정도로 목소리를 높였습니다.
Even if I'm drunk and can't control myself
술에 취해 주체할 수 없어도
I don't want to hurt anyone.
나는 누구에게도 상처를 입히고 싶지 않습니다.
too bright
너무 밝다
Madam, please don't poke me in the eye.
부인, 제 눈을 찌르지 마세요.
How soft is this?
이 얼마나 부드러운가요?
No, sir, you didn't hit me.
아니요, 선생님, 당신은 저를 때리지 않았습니다.
Now let's go to Fahrenheit Mansion.
이제 화씨저택으로 가겠습니다.
Please prepare a carriage for me.
나를 위해 마차를 준비해주세요.
Madam, why all of a sudden?
부인, 갑자기 왜요?
Are you coming back soon?
곧 다시 오실 건가요?
I'm afraid that Mrs. Hua will do that...
화 부인이 그러실까봐 두렵습니다...
I have been avoiding this issue for a long time.
나는 오랫동안 이 문제를 피해왔습니다.
Now is the time to face the truth.
이제는 진실을 직시해야 할 때입니다.
"Hua Family House"
"후아 패밀리 하우스"
Madam, please.
부인, 부탁드립니다.
It's in the Now Butler Hua library.
나우 버틀러 후아 도서실에 있어요.
He asked me to welcome you.
그는 나에게 당신을 환영해 달라고 부탁했습니다.
And what about my mother?
그리고 우리 어머니는 어떻습니까?
Madam Hua is not feeling well.
화 부인은 몸이 좋지 않습니다.
So she stayed home and rested.
그래서 그녀는 집에서 쉬었습니다.
I think he's still angry.
그 사람이 아직도 화가 나 있는 것 같아요.
During this time I didn't pay much attention to her.
이 기간 동안 나는 그녀에게 더 많은 관심을 기울이지 않았습니다.
it's crazy?
미쳤어?
Your brother is still in prison.
네 동생은 아직 감옥에 있다.
But do you still miss the Mu family?
그런데 아직도 뮤 가족이 그리워요?
You need to make the most of your time.
시간을 최대한 활용해야 합니다.
Think about how to make your owner love you.
주인이 당신을 사랑하게 만드는 방법을 생각해 보세요.
My master will never forgive me.
주인님은 절대 용서하지 않으실 거예요.
And I found a way
그리고 난 방법을 찾았어
I can't intervene in Shen'er's case.
Shen'er의 사건에 개입할 수 없습니다.
If my father wanted me to, I got out of prison.
아버지가 원하시면 나는 감옥에서 나왔다.
You need to listen to me.
내 말을 들어야 해요.
What can you do?
당신은 무엇을 할 수 있나요?
last month
지난 달
Have you tried several methods?
여러 가지 방법을 시도해 보셨죠?
And my brother is still in prison.
그리고 내 동생은 아직도 감옥에 갇혀 있어요.
Father has another way.
아버지에게는 다른 방법이 있습니다.
Besides, do you trust me or you?
게다가 나 아니면 당신을 믿나요?
What changed you so much?
무엇이 당신을 그렇게 변화시켰나요?
Who motivated you?
누가 당신을 자극했습니까?
I'm just trying to atone for your sins.
나는 단지 당신의 죄를 속죄하려고 노력하고 있습니다.
Father, I don't think you've ever killed anyone.
아버지, 제 생각에는 당신이 사람을 죽인 적이 없습니다.
But do you know what you did wrong?
하지만 당신이 잘못했다는 것을 알고 있습니까?
No, I should say the Hua family.
아니, Hua 가족이라고 해야 할까요.
How many mistakes have you made?
당신은 얼마나 많은 실수를 저질렀습니까?
Where can merchants have clean hands?
상인들이 깨끗한 손을 가질 수 있는 곳은 어디입니까?
I didn't know you were so naive. Since when?
당신이 그렇게 순진한 줄은 몰랐어요. 언제부터?
I think you are just being diligent and kind.
당신은 단지 부지런하고 친절하다고 생각합니다.
Can I get promoted like this?
내가 이렇게 승진할 수 있을까?
it's me.
나야.
That's hard work
그거 열심히 하는 거야
Climb the ranks to become a butler
집사가 되기 위해 계급을 올라가다
So you came to argue with me.
그래서 당신은 나와 논쟁하러 왔습니다.
You can stay here.
여기에 머물 수 있습니다.
When talking about justice
정의를 말할 때
Don't forget your last name.
자신의 성을 잊지 마세요.
Of course, I will never forget you.
물론, 나는 당신을 결코 잊지 않을 것입니다.
Because my last name is Hua.
내 성이 화(Hua)이기 때문이에요.
and you are my father
그리고 당신은 나의 아버지입니다
So I didn't turn my back.
그래서 나는 등을 돌리지 않았습니다.
To the Fahrenheit family
화씨 가족에게
Father, will you listen to me or believe me?
아버지, 제 말을 들어주실 건가요, 아니면 믿으실 건가요?
That's not important.
그것은 중요하지 않습니다.
I will use my means to inform the Father.
나는 내 방법을 사용하여 아버지께 알리겠습니다.
wealth and honor
부와 명예
what you wanted in the past
네가 과거에 원했던 것
It shows that you have reached a high standard.
높은 수준에 도달했음을 보여줍니다.
Anyway, you are an idiot.
어쨌든 당신은 바보입니다.
owner...
소유자...
Do you want to hit me again?
또 나를 때리고 싶니?
But this time I won't give up.
하지만 이번에는 포기하지 않겠습니다.
Again like before
또 예전처럼
Now I'm the only one
이제 나뿐인 사람이야
My father will rely on me and guide me. My older brother is out of prison.
아버지가 의지하여 이끌어 주실 것입니다 형이 감옥에서 나왔습니다.
When can I help my brother?
내가 동생을 도울 수 있다면 언제?
Dad needs to calm down.
아버지는 진정하셔야 합니다.
Then come to me and find out.
그럼 나한테 와서 알아봐.
When will your brother be released from prison?
네 동생은 언제 감옥에서 풀려날 거야?
Father, don't forget. what i just said
아버지, 잊지 마세요. 내가 방금 말한 것
How long will my brother be in prison?
내 동생은 언제까지 감옥에 갇힐까요?
It depends on it. How quickly do you plan to act?
그것은 그것에 달려 있습니다. 얼마나 빨리 행동할 예정입니까?
Madam, are you going or not?
부인, 가시나요, 안 가시나요?
Butler Hua gave me an order. Please prepare lunch.
집사 후아(Butler Hua)가 나에게 명령을 내렸습니다. 점심을 준비해주세요.
I still have work to do, so it would be better not to eat.
아직 할 일이 있으니 먹지 않는 게 낫겠다.
Madam, why don’t you go see Madam Hua?
부인, 화 부인을 만나러 가지 않겠습니까?
During this time she was unable to eat or sleep.
이 기간 동안 그녀는 먹거나 잠을 잘 수 없었습니다.
And I lost a lot of weight.
그리고 살이 많이 빠졌어요.
- No, - Qian'er.
- 아니, - 치엔얼.
How long does it take to get home?
집에 오는데 얼마나 걸리나요?
Why are you in such a hurry to go back?
왜 그렇게 서둘러 돌아가나요?
I have a lot of work to do.
나는 할 일이 많다.
We have to hurry.
서둘러야 해요.
Otherwise, I'm afraid Mom will think I'm not doing anything.
그렇지 않으면 두려워요 엄마는 내가 아무것도 안 한다고 생각할 거예요.
For those things, wait a little longer. No damage.
그런 것들은 조금 더 기다려요. 손상되지 않습니다.
I heard you're back.
당신이 돌아왔다고 들었어요.
So, we prepared some of your favorite snacks.
그래서 여러분이 좋아하는 간식을 준비했어요.
Please stay with me for a moment.
잠시 동안 나와 함께 있어주세요.
no.
아닙니다.
Come on, come on.
어서, 어서.
I have something to say, so please go.
할 말이 있는데 가세요.
this
이것
Have some.
좀 드세요.
I made your favorite dessert.
네가 가장 좋아하는 디저트를 만들어 줬어.
You haven't been home for a while.
당신은 한동안 집에 없었습니다.
Let's try it and see. Is the taste still the same?
시도해보고 살펴 보겠습니다. 맛은 아직도 그대로인가요?
This is delicious.
이 맛있어요.
Your younger brother likes it too.
네 동생도 좋아하잖아.
I remember making dessert.
디저트를 만들었던 기억이 나네요.
And he'll be watching from my side
그리고 그 사람은 내 옆에서 지켜볼 거야
Once completed, he will quickly bring it to you.
완료되면 그는 빨리 그것을 당신에게 가져올 것입니다.
And he ate the rest.
그리고 그는 나머지를 먹었습니다.
Only after eating my fill
배불리 먹은 후에야
like i said before
내가 전에 말했듯이
I'll take care of your business myself.
오빠 일은 내가 직접 처리할게.
Mom, you don't have to tell me.
어머니, 저한테 말씀하실 필요 없어요.
With such beautiful words
이렇게 아름다운 말로
i know
알아요
you probably think
당신은 아마 생각
Am I biased against your sister?
내가 네 동생에게 편견을 갖고 있는 걸까?
Anyway, he is. my only son
어쨌든 그는 그렇습니다. 내 하나뿐인 아들
You haven't had a son yet.
당신은 아직 아들을 낳지 않았습니다.
So I don't know.
그래서 나는 모른다.
How important is your son?
아들이 얼마나 중요합니까?
“How could you not know?”
"어떻게 모를 수 있니?"
“It was like this in my past life.”
"전생에는 이랬어요."
“He’s not interested in me at all.”
"나한테는 전혀 관심이 없어."
“I only care about my son.”
"나는 내 아들에게만 관심이 있어요."
when you were young
당신이 어렸을 때
I rarely take you to my old house.
나는 당신을 나의 오래된 집에 데려가는 경우가 거의 없습니다.
to meet grandpa
할아버지를 만나러
I think
제 생각에는
You know what I'm thinking.
내가 무슨 생각을 하는지 당신도 알잖아요.
Are you my grandfather or not?
당신은 내 할아버지인가요, 아닌가요?
You are still very young.
당신은 아직 아주 어립니다.
When Grandma Died
할머니가 돌아가셨을 때
Surely you remember them.
분명히 당신은 그들을 기억합니다.
You can't.
당신은 할 수 없습니다.
What happened to grandma?
할머니는 어떻게 됐나요?
I never said you.
난 당신을 말한 적이 없어요.
You are now someone's wife.
당신은 이제 누군가의 아내입니다.
It's time to talk about it.
그것에 대해 말할 시간입니다.
your grandmother
당신의 할머니
Be a proper wife According to your grandfather's laws
올바른 아내가 되십시오 할아버지의 법에 따르면
Let me be a legitimate child even though I am called to do so.
내가 부름을 받았는데도 합법적인 아이가 되자
I also did not receive treatment.
나 역시 치료를 받지 못했다.
concubine's son
첩의 아들
Do you know why?
이유를 아시나요?
Because of your grandmother
네 할머니 때문에
gave birth to me a daughter
나한테 딸을 낳았어
my daughter
내 딸
today is your birthday
오늘은 너의 생일이야
What do you want? as a birthday present
당신은 무엇을 원하세요? 생일 선물로
I don't want anything from you.
나는 당신에게서 아무것도 원하지 않습니다.
I just wish my dad would play with me all day.
나는 단지 아버지가 나와 하루종일 놀아주셨으면 좋겠다.
Okay, what should we play?
알았어, 뭐 하고 놀까?
Let's agree.
동의합시다.
Master, the young master coughed non-stop.
스승님, 어린 스승님은 쉬지 않고 기침을 했습니다.
Pastor Jang, please.
장 목사님이 부탁드립니다.
Go and check out the symptoms.
가서 증상을 살펴보세요.
If he's sick, go to the doctor.
그가 아프면 의사에게 가세요.
Sir, you don't know anything about medicine.
선생님, 의학에 대해 아무것도 모르시네요.
You can't say that.
그렇게 말할 수는 없습니다.
I will go and take a look.
나는 가서 살펴볼 것이다.
Father, you just promised me.
아버지, 방금 저에게 약속하셨습니다.
He said he would play with me all day
하루종일 나랑 놀아준다고
Now you are broken.
이제 당신은 망가졌습니다.
Your little brother is sick.
당신의 남동생이 아프다.
But I still want to play again
하지만 그래도 다시 플레이하고 싶어
I will go and take a look.
나는 가서 살펴볼 것이다.
He's doing well. I'll come again.
그 사람은 잘 지내요. 또 올게요.
- Father - Elder
- 아버지 - 장로님
- mother's son - father
- 어머니의 아들 - 아버지
to let go...
놓치다...
Your master has given you this. It's a birthday present.
주인님이 이것을 당신에게 주셨습니다. 생일 선물이에요.
What do you have in your hands?
당신의 손에 무엇이 있습니까?
A jade bracelet given to me by my father.
아버지가 주신 옥팔찌.
I want that too.
나도 그걸 원해.
You are a boy. What are you going to do with it?
당신은 소년입니다. 그걸로 무엇을 하시겠습니까?
I don't care.
나는 상관하지 않는다.
I want everything you have.
나는 당신이 가진 모든 것을 원합니다.
What makes you think? You can take my things.
무엇이 당신을 생각하게 만드나요? 내 물건을 가져가도 돼요.
I want to teach you a lesson.
나는 당신에게 교훈을 가르쳐주고 싶습니다.
Instead of mom?
엄마 대신?
Let's see, I am your father's son.
어디 보자, 나는 네 아버지의 아들이다.
You are just a daughter.
당신은 단지 딸입니다.
You have to get married sooner or later.
조만간 결혼해야합니다.
at that time
그때에
The whole house will be mine.
집 전체가 내 것이 될 것이다.
If you dare to hit me
감히 나를 때릴 생각이라면
I will banish your mother and make her a beggar.
네 어머니를 추방하여 거지로 만들겠다.
Mr. Noi Chao
노이 차오 씨
Madam, your daughter is the eldest.
부인, 따님이 맏이입니다.
How could she do this to her brother?
어떻게 그녀가 남동생에게 이런 짓을 할 수 있었을까?
So how?
그래서 방법?
I will teach the queen's sons, daughters and wives.
왕비의 아들 딸과 아내를 가르 칠 것입니다
This is normal.
여기는 정상입니다.
I know you can't have a son.
나는 당신이 아들을 낳을 수 없다는 것을 압니다.
So you don't like my son.
그래서 당신은 내 아들을 좋아하지 않습니다.
But even though my son is the son of a concubine
그런데 내 아들이 첩의 아들인데도
He is also the heir. In the future of Mr.
그는 또한 상속자입니다. 씨의 미래에는
If the person is seriously injured
그 사람이 심각한 부상을 입은 경우
The master's family line ends here.
주인의 가문은 여기서 끝나게 됩니다.
- There it is - that's enough.
- 거기 있군요 - 그거면 충분해요
Why all the fuss?
왜 그렇게 소란스러운 걸까요?
you...
너...
I'm sorry about your brother.
네 남동생 일은 안타깝다.
sibling
형제
After all, harming others is always wrong.
결국, 다른 사람에게 해를 끼치는 것은 항상 잘못된 것입니다.
Besides, you are his sister.
게다가 당신은 그의 여동생이에요.
I need to apologize.
사과해야합니다.
your younger brother
당신의 남동생
Sir, I will yield to him.
선생님, 제가 그에게 양보하겠습니다.
And from now on I don't want anything else.
그리고 이제부터 나는 다른 것을 원하지 않습니다.
owner...
소유자...
Your grandfather has never been violent towards me.
당신의 할아버지 나에게 폭력적인 행동을 한 적이 없습니다.
But every time we argue
하지만 말다툼을 할 때마다
with my younger brother
남동생과 함께
He will always be biased in favor of his son.
그는 항상 아들에게 유리하게 편향될 것입니다.
he felt it
그는 그것을 느꼈다
Sooner or later his daughter will have to get married.
조만간 그의 딸은 결혼해야 할 것입니다.
And someone else's
그리고 다른 사람의 것
your grandmother can't have a son
당신의 할머니 아들을 낳지 못함
And she had to suffer all her life.
그리고 그녀는 평생 고통을 겪어야 했습니다.
I don't want to live like that anymore.
나는 더 이상 그렇게 살고 싶지 않습니다.
And I don't want you to suffer like me.
그리고 난 당신을 원하지 않아요 너도 나처럼 고생해야 해.
Who looks like your father? Giving all my heart and soul
누가 네 아버지처럼 생겼어? 마음과 영혼을 모두 바치는
to the factory
공장으로
And I don't plan on having a concubine.
그리고 나는 첩을 가질 계획도 없습니다.
Because I gave birth.
제가 출산을 했기 때문이죠.
Your older brother is your first child.
네 형이 첫째 아이야.
Like if I give birth to a daughter, you'll be alone.
내가 딸을 낳으면 너 혼자인 것처럼
At the Hua Family Mansion
후아 패밀리 맨션에서
There must have been many concubines.
첩도 많았을 것입니다.
Mom, you said you had to work hard.
어머니, 고생하셔야 한다고 하셨습니다.
Because of prejudice
편견 때문에
Then why did you become a human?
그럼 왜 사람이 되었나요?
Who is also prejudiced against sons?
아들에게도 편견을 갖는 사람은 누구입니까?
Qian'er, it's not the same.
Qian'er, 그것은 동일하지 않습니다.
Shen'er is your real brother.
Shen'er는 당신의 진짜 형제입니다.
He will protect you.
그 사람이 당신을 보호해줄 거예요
Because you are of the same blood
왜냐하면 당신은 같은 혈통
Without my brother
형 없이
What do you think life at the head residence is like?
종가 저택에서의 생활이 다음과 같다고 생각하십니까?
Would it be this easy?
이렇게 쉬울까요?
Your father is going to marry another woman.
네 아버지는 다른 여자와 결혼하실 거야.
whenever
언제든지
And I could only watch helplessly
그리고 나는 무기력하게 바라볼 수 밖에 없었어
If the father had another son
아버지에게 아들이 하나 더 있다면
You need to pay attention to him. more than usual
당신은 그에게주의를 기울여야합니다. 평소보다 더
Without the support of the Fahrenheit family,
화씨 가문의 지지가 없다면
Your owner may have treated you badly.
당신의 주인이 당신을 나쁘게 대했을 수도 있습니다.
And you will suffer in silence.
그리고 당신은 침묵 속에서 고통받을 것입니다.
At the head residence
종가 저택에서
For this reason I have hastened for you.
이 때문에 나는 당신을 위해 서둘러 왔습니다.
Have a son as soon as possible.
가능한 한 빨리 아들을 낳으십시오.
Even if my father ignores me
아버지가 무시해도
Your position is unwavering.
당신의 입장은 흔들리지 않습니다.
And you have a brother.
그리고 당신에게는 형제가 있습니다.
No matter how stupid that person is
그 사람이 아무리 바보같아도
He is the only One we can rely on.
그분은 우리가 의지할 수 있는 유일한 분입니다.
Did you understand?
이해했나요?
That's it.
그게 다야.
My mother has never lived. The same goes for life and death situations.
어머니는 살아본 적이 없습니다. 삶과 죽음의 상황에서도 마찬가지입니다.
No wonder you say this.
당신이 이렇게 말하는 것은 이상하지 않습니다.
stupid kid
멍청한 꼬마
Do you understand what I'm saying?
내가 말하는 것을 이해 했어?
What does it say about life and death?
삶과 죽음에 대해 무엇을 말하는가?
There is nothing.
아무것도 없습니다.
i just want to say
나는 단지 말하고 싶다
I will help my brother get out of prison.
나는 내 동생이 감옥에서 나오도록 도와줄 것이다.
So mom, don't worry.
그러니 어머니, 걱정하지 마세요.
great.
좋아요.
good
좋은
Now, try some.
자, 좀 먹어보세요.
Eat again.
다시 먹어라.
How long does it take to get home?
집에 오는데 얼마나 걸리나요?
I salute you
당신에게 경의를 표합니다
Sir, you have eaten the soup.
선생님, 수프를 드셨습니다.
Was it the night before I sent it or not?
내가 보낸 것 전날 밤이었나요, 아니었나요?
Song An brought it to me.
송안이 그것을 나에게 가져왔다.
The taste is pretty good.
맛은 꽤 좋습니다.
I'm glad to hear that news.
그 소식을 들으니 기쁘군요.
I feel anxious if I add too much sugar.
설탕을 너무 많이 넣으면 불안해요.
You might think it's too sweet.
너무 달콤하다고 생각할 수도 있습니다.
It's kind of sweet. But there's still enough to eat.
좀 달콤해요. 하지만 아직 먹기엔 충분해요.
This 2 nights and 3 days
이번 2박 3일
Your second uncle works at Hwangcheong .
당신의 둘째 삼촌은 황청에서 일을 하십니다 .
It's nice to be in one place.
한곳에 있어서 좋네요.
My mother hasn't returned yet.
어머니는 아직 돌아오지 않으셨습니다.
if you have time
시간이 있으면
Then go see your uncle.
그럼 삼촌을 만나러 가세요.
To my uncle
삼촌에게
He's going to be my father's younger brother.
내 아버지의 남동생이 될 거야
But we are not close to each other.
하지만 우리는 서로 가깝지 않습니다.
I don't want to disturb him.
나는 그를 방해하고 싶지 않습니다.
Bad people have a side. That's also unfortunate.
나쁜 사람에게는 일면이 있다. 그것도 안타깝습니다.
Mistress, this is all money.
여주인, 이게 다 돈이에요.
It has been withdrawn from the factory.
공장에서 철수된 것입니다.
This is enough.
이 정도면 충분합니다.
- Qianzi - Lord, madam.
- Qianzi - 주님, 부인.
Take this and keep it.
이것을 받아 보관하세요.
You, mistress.
당신, 여주인.
Madam, what are you going to do with all that money?
부인, 그 많은 돈으로 무엇을 하려고 하시나요?
Just use it for important purposes.
그냥 중요한 용도로 사용하세요.
chenzi
첸쯔
Have you ever wanted to be free?
자유롭고 싶었던 적이 있나요?
And left the head family residence.
그리고 종가 저택을 떠났다
Should I go and live my own life?
가서 자신의 삶을 살까?
Madam, what does that mean?
부인, 그게 무슨 뜻이에요?
Becoming a servant I'm wasting my time here every day
하인이 되다 매일 여기서 시간을 낭비하고 있어
Not a good idea at all.
전혀 좋은 생각이 아닙니다.
Madam, are you going to kick me out?
부인, 저를 쫓아내실 건가요?
What did I do wrong?
내가 뭘 잘못했나요?
No, I'm not after you, I...
아니, 난 당신을 쫓는 게 아니야, 난...
Never mind. Stop talking about this.
신경쓰지 마세요. 이 얘기는 그만하세요.
You are such a crybaby.
당신은 정말 울보입니다.
How can I live life without you?
당신이 없다면 나는 어떻게 인생을 살 수 있을까요?
If you kick me out, I'll die.
쫓아내면 난 죽는다
Don't act like a crybaby. Same as Qianzi.
울보처럼 행동하지 마세요. Qianzi와 같습니다.
And don't forget to see your doctor.
그리고 의사를 만나는 것을 잊지 마세요.
Please give me some good medicine.
좋은 약 좀 주세요.
Please come and treat the wound on my face.
오셔서 얼굴의 상처를 치료해 주십시오.
Don't just use a bandage.
붕대만 사용하지 마세요.
Leave no scars.
흉터를 남기지 마십시오.
On a handsome face
잘생긴 얼굴에
Please ask me first.
먼저 부탁드리겠습니다.
One person is a crybaby.
한 사람은 울보입니다.
The other person feels embarrassed.
상대방은 부끄러워합니다.
Why are people around me so sensitive?
내 주변 사람들은 왜 이렇게 예민한 걸까요?
Sir, we have recorded the damage.
선생님, 피해 상황을 기록했습니다.
From the Lee family
리 가문 출신
All people born into the Zhang family were eliminated
장 가문에서 태어난 사람들은 모두 제거되었습니다
And calculate the amount
그리고 금액을 계산해 보세요
All outstanding balances have been paid.
미납금이 모두 완료되었습니다.
We warned them several times.
우리는 그들에게 여러 번 경고했습니다.
However, Jang's family still refused to pay.
그러나 장씨 가족은 여전히 ​​지불을 거부했다.
teacher
선생님
Teacher, please.
선생님, 제발요.
What problem did Young Master Ho have this time?
이번에 호영사님은 무슨 문제가 있었나요?
He said while crying.
그는 울면서 말했다.
He was bitten by a rat.
그는 쥐에게 물렸습니다.
You can get sick and die in prison.
감옥에서 병들고 죽을 수도 있다
when he was bitten
그가 물렸을 때
Take him to a doctor and check him out.
의사를 데리고 가서 그를 확인해 보세요.
We took him but he wouldn't let the doctor.
우리는 그를 데려갔지만 그는 의사를 허락하지 않았습니다.
Please touch him.
그를 만져주세요.
He said he was afraid he might be poisoned.
독살당할까봐 두렵다고 하더군요.
great.
좋아요.
When he still had the strength to cry
그에게 아직 울 힘이 남아 있었을 때
It has been proven that there is nothing serious.
심각한 것은 없다는 것이 증명됐다.
Please make sure you eat three meals a day regularly.
하루에 세 끼를 규칙적으로 먹게 해주세요.
And you don't need to pay attention to him.
그리고 당신은 그에게 관심을 기울일 필요가 없습니다.
Teacher, please...
선생님, 제발...
He was locked up for a month.
그는 한 달 동안 갇혀 있었습니다.
When will the investigation begin?
조사는 언제 시작되나요?
last month
지난 달
All the guards were very tired.
모든 경비원은 매우 피곤했습니다.
Please, because of him.
그 사람 때문에 제발.
you think i can
당신은 내가 할 수 있다고 생각
Is it okay to interrogate me at any time?
언제든지 심문해도 괜찮나요?
First, wait for the warrant.
먼저 영장을 기다리세요.
You don't need to ask any more.
더 이상 물어볼 필요가 없습니다.
If nothing happens, you can leave.
별 일 없으면 가셔도 됩니다.
Accept it.
그것을 받아들이십시오.
Be sure to come and get it.
꼭 오셔서 받아보세요.
"Middle-aged Mansion"
"중가 저택"
Confessor Mu, would you like to read it tomorrow?
무 참회자님, 내일 읽어보실래요?
Be careful as it may hurt your eyes.
눈이 다칠 수 있으니 조심하세요.
Anyway, I can't sleep.
어쨌든 잠이 안 와요.
It's also good to read a book for a while.
잠시 책을 읽는 것도 좋습니다.
It's been almost a month now.
이제 거의 한 달이 지났습니다.
A brave villain who harmed you.
당신에게 해를 끼친 용감한 악당
He is still imprisoned without any interrogation.
아직도 아무런 심문도 받지 못한 채 투옥되어 있습니다.
And the owner did nothing.
그리고 주인은 아무것도 하지 않았습니다.
I watched Mistress today. Go outside again.
오늘은 미스트리스(Mistress)를 봤습니다. 다시 밖으로 나갑니다.
She didn't seem fazed.
그녀는 당황하지 않은 것 같았습니다.
She went out to buy things.
그녀는 물건을 사러 나갔다.
And when I visited my parents nothing seemed to have happened.
그리고 부모님을 방문 아무 일도 일어나지 않은 것 같습니다.
This issue is not about her.
이 문제는 그녀에 관한 것이 아닙니다.
She wouldn't have felt anything.
그녀는 아무것도 느끼지 않았을 것입니다.
But that villain, I am her brother.
그런데 그 악당 나는 그녀의 형제입니다.
He was so scared that he ran away.
그는 너무 겁이 나서 도망갔습니다.
But the owner did not come to comfort him.
그러나 주인은 그를 위로하러 오지 않았습니다.
Besides, he lets his mistress do whatever she wants.
게다가 그는 여주인이 원하는 대로 하도록 내버려둡니다.
He is prejudiced against her. There are already too many.
그는 그녀에게 편견이 있습니다. 이미 너무 많습니다.
Continue like this
이대로 계속
If you suddenly lose hope
갑자기 희망을 잃으면
Let the criminals go.
범죄자들을 놓아주세요.
That's not surprising at all.
전혀 놀라운 일이 아닙니다.
Please go and get me some water.
가서 물 좀 가져다주세요.
I want to shower and sleep.
샤워하고 자고 싶어요.
One of the servants, the mistress housekeeper Hua, sent this.
하인 중 한 명인 여주인 가정부 Hua가 이것을 보냈습니다.
Your father may be stubborn.
아버지가 완고하실 수도 있어요.
And refuse to hear the truth
그리고 진실을 듣기를 거부합니다
But there are enough problems. only son
그러나 문제는 충분합니다. 외아들의
He acted really quickly.
그는 정말 빨리 행동했어요.
Madam, who are these people?
부인, 이 사람들은 누구입니까?
Call Hua Rongzhou.
화룽저우(Hua Rongzhou)에 전화해 보세요.
You, mistress.
당신, 여주인.
I need help. This task is complicated.
도움이 필요해요 이 작업은 복잡합니다.
And there's no one I can trust.
그리고 저는 믿을 수 있는 사람이 없어요.
It's nearby.
근처에 있어요.
Can you help me with this errand?
이 심부름 좀 도와주실 수 있나요?
I already have it, sir.
이미 가지고 있어요, 선생님.
I am willing to die for you.
나는 당신을 위해 기꺼이 죽을 수 있습니다.
It's not that serious, just wake up.
별로 심각한 건 아닌데, 일어나세요.
Here is a list
여기에는 목록이 있습니다
And I have enough money
그리고 돈은 충분해
Collect their debts. All within 3 days.
그들의 빚을 모으십시오. 모두 3일 안에요.
I asked for a hostess.
나는 여주인을 요청했습니다.
Our Little Sentry I am now an adult.
우리의 작은 보초 나는 이제 성인이 되었습니다.
He can handle important matters on his own.
그는 중요한 문제를 스스로 처리할 수 있습니다.
That person is there.
그 사람이 거기 있어요.
"빚"
"빚"
Well done
잘하셨어요
I think I underestimated you.
내가 당신을 과소평가한 것 같군요.
Now just one day has passed.
이제 딱 하루가 지났습니다.
Job done.
작업을 완료했습니다.
Go and call Qianzi.
가서 Qianzi에게 전화해 보세요.
I'll handle it.
내가 처리할게.
early in the morning
이른 아침에
Please, mistress.
부탁해요, 여주인님.
government
정부
Why handwriting?
손글씨는 왜?
It seems different from before.
이전과는 달라진 것 같습니다.
My right hand is injured.
오른손이 다쳤어요.
So it affects your handwriting.
그래서 필기에 영향을 미칩니다.
A woman's hands are very precious.
여자의 손은 매우 귀중합니다.
Even if the owner gets angry
주인이 화를 내도
He couldn't do that to you.
그 사람은 당신에게 그런 짓을 할 수 없었어요.
Madam, you were an expert. Gogeumnori, Gogeumnori
부인, 당신은 전문가였죠. 고금놀이, 바둑놀이
calligraphy and painting
서예와 그림
But now he's ruined everything.
하지만 이제 그는 모든 것을 망쳤습니다.
Thanks to that, please take this and give it to Zong Yeran.
그것 덕분에 이것을 받아 종예란에게 주세요.
“Divorce certificate”
"이혼증명서"
Madam, this...
부인, 이게...
What about divorce papers?
이혼 서류는 어떻습니까?
I have other business to attend to. hurry up, please.
나는 참석할 다른 일이 있습니다. 서둘러주세요.
Madame Chao
마담 차오
this is...
이것은...
Mr. Mu’s wife said this.
무씨의 아내는 이렇게 말했다.
She was in a bad mood. And he won't let anyone see him.
그녀는 기분이 좋지 않았습니다. 그리고 누구도 그를 볼 수 없도록 할 것입니다.
Do you have light body skills?
당신은 가벼운 몸 기술을 가지고 있습니까?
I have it.
갖고 있어요.
take me beyond the wall
날 벽 너머로 데려가줘
Stop bragging and hurry.
자랑은 그만하고 서두르세요.
What should we do?
우리는 무엇을 해야 합니까?
You have to hold me in your arms or ride me on your back.
나를 품에 안아주거나 등에 태워야 합니다.
Hurry up.
서둘러요.
Hurry up!
서둘러요!
Madam, I'm sorry.
부인, 죄송해요.
How did you get here?
여기 어떻게 들어왔나요?
Non-penitents do not accept guests.
무 참회자는 손님을 받아들이지 않습니다.
I can't go in.
나는 들어갈 수 없다.
Mu's concubine
무의 첩
let's go.
가자.
Yamhwa, it's you...
얌화야, 너야...
What do you want?
당신은 무엇을 원하세요?
I want to talk to you. But they wouldn't let me in.
난 당신과 얘기하고 싶어. 하지만 그들은 나를 들여보내지 않았습니다.
So I had to find another entrance.
그래서 다른 입구를 찾아야 했어요.
I have nothing to talk to you about.
나는 당신과 이야기 할 것이 없습니다.
Read this first and then speak.
이것을 먼저 읽고 나서 말하세요.
What does it mean?
무슨 뜻이에요?
Are you threatening me?
나를 협박하는 겁니까?
No, I'm here to make a deal.
아니요, 저는 거래를 하러 왔습니다.
agreement or
합의 또는
With the debt of all servants
전 종의 빚으로
Among the Mu family?
뮤 가족 중?
Please send Hwasen.
화센을 보내주세요.
Then I will pay off all my debt.
그러면 빚을 모두 갚겠습니다.
The servant of the former Mu family gives you
전 무 가문의 하인이 당신에게
And if I don’t want to, just send Hua Shen away.
그리고 내가 원하지 않는다면 Hua Shen을 보내십시오.
What will you do?
당신은 무엇을 할 것인가?
I'm not here to threaten you.
나는 당신을 위협하기 위해 여기 온 것이 아닙니다.
So I won't accept it. the life of your species
그래서 나는 그것을 받아들이지 않을 것입니다. 당신 종의 삶
Come as a negotiation tool
협상 도구로 오세요
Didn't you come here to threaten me?
나한테 협박하러 온 거 아니었어?
So what does this mean?
그렇다면 이것은 무엇을 의미합니까?
This is a warning.
경고입니다.
You can find debt products.
채무상품을 찾을 수 있어요.
Easily for your entire species
당신의 전 종의 용이하게
This proves that I can do more.
이것은 내가 더 많은 일을 할 수 있다는 것을 증명합니다.
whether you believe it or not
당신이 믿든 안 믿든
If it's a matter of negotiation
협상의 문제라면
I have more cards than you.
나는 당신보다 더 많은 카드를 가지고 있습니다.
Mistakes made by Hwasen
화센이 저지른 실수
I am not against it.
나는 그것에 반대하지 않습니다.
He will pay a huge price.
그는 엄청난 대가를 치러야 합니다.
But because of what he didn't do
하지만 그 사람이 하지 않은 일 때문에
I won't allow you. He also made false accusations.
나는 당신을 허용하지 않습니다. 그도 거짓으로 고발했습니다.
Each person's opinion on right and wrong
옳고 그름에 대한 각자의 견해
to be different
달라지다
Will commit a serious crime against the Hua family
화씨 가족에게 심각한 범죄를 저지를 것이다
We don't have to pay for it.
우리는 그 비용을 지불할 필요가 없습니다.
For what we didn't do
우리가 하지 않은 일에
Therefore, Muyao
그러므로 무야오
Because I want revenge
복수를 원하니까
And turn the case around
그리고 사건을 뒤집어
Come and be honest.
와서 솔직하게 대해주세요.
I won't interfere. your quest for truth
나는 방해하지 않을 것이다. 진실을 향한 당신의 탐구
But if you keep using dirty methods
하지만 더러운 방법을 계속 사용한다면
I won't pretend I didn't see it.
못 본 척은 안 할게요.
People who wanted to punish Huashen
화센을 처벌하고 싶었던 사람들
This is Yeongju.
영주입니다.
What do you think you will get if you come to me?
나한테 오면 뭘 얻을 것 같아?
Mu Yao
무 야오
Don't belittle your condition.
자신의 상태를 얕보지 마십시오.
In Jong Ye-ran’s mind.
종예란의 마음속에.
And do you think Zhong Yeran doesn’t know?
그리고 종예란은 모른다고 생각하시나요?
This time we set the scene.
이번에는 장면을 설정했습니다.
People in love are really stupid.
사랑에 빠진 사람들은 정말 어리석습니다.
last month
지난 달
Zhong Ye Lan did not give any orders.
Zhong Ye Lan은 어떤 명령도 내리지 않았습니다.
punish my brother
내 동생을 처벌해
And just lock it up
그리고 그냥 가둬둬
What do you think is the reason?
그 이유가 무엇이라고 생각하시나요?
He was angry that day.
그날 그는 화를 냈습니다.
Until I almost killed my brother.
내 동생을 거의 죽일 뻔할 때까지
Don't lie to me.
나에게 거짓말하지 마십시오.
Deep down, you know.
깊은 곳에서는 알잖아요.
Am I telling the truth or not?
내가 진실을 말하는지 아닌지
Besides, Zhong Ye Lan understands you.
게다가 Zhong Ye Lan은 당신을 이해합니다.
more than I
나보다 더
Although anger plays a role
분노가 영향을 미치긴 하지만
With his decision in the first place
애초에 그의 결정으로
He noticed something suspicious.
그는 의심스러운 점을 발견했습니다.
Later when it calms down
나중에 진정되면
No matter how ridiculous Hua Shen is
Hua Shen이 아무리 우스꽝스러워도
He probably wouldn't dare come and cause chaos.
그는 아마도 감히 와서 혼란을 일으키지 못할 것입니다.
At Lee's wedding
이 씨의 결혼식에서
You can't even fool me.
당신은 나를 속일 수도 없습니다.
What makes you think you can fool him?
당신이 그를 속일 수 있다고 생각하는 이유는 무엇입니까?
Why do you think so? I know him better than I know myself.
왜 그렇게 생각하는가? 나는 나보다 그를 더 잘 안다.
It's not that I know him better.
내가 그를 더 잘 아는 것은 아니다.
It's just Jong-ye.
그냥 종예란
Accidentally exposing one's own sins
실수로 자신의 죄를 폭로함
In front of me a few days ago
며칠 전 내 앞에서
You don't want to listen to me.
당신은 내 말을 듣고 싶지 않습니다.
And I don't want it now. I would say the same thing.
그리고 지금은 원하지 않습니다. 나도 같은 방식으로 이야기하겠습니다.
My heart aches.
내 마음이 괴로워요.
I'm not in the mood to argue with you.
나는 당신과 논쟁할 기분이 아닙니다.
Don't mess with me.
나한테 장난치지 마.
Hua Chen...
화첸...
Doing so will put your mind at ease.
그렇게 하면 마음이 편해진다.
If you want to kill my brother, please.
내 동생을 죽이고 싶다면 제발.
You take advantage of the fact that:
당신은 다음과 같은 사실을 이용합니다.
Zhong Yueran likes you.
종웨란이 당신을 좋아합니다.
And think of a plan
그리고 계획을 생각해
It's full of loopholes.
허점이 가득합니다.
If I hadn't stopped him that day
그날 내가 그를 막지 않았다면
He would have killed my brother.
그는 내 동생을 죽였을 겁니다.
With his sword gone
그의 검이 사라진 채로
And you will have avenged Linglong.
그리고 당신은 Linglong의 복수를 했을 것입니다.
Huaqian
화첸
I never dreamed I would see this side of you.
내가 당신의 이런 면을 보게 될 줄은 꿈에도 몰랐어요.
But I want to remind you.
하지만 나는 당신에게 상기시키고 싶습니다.
The most fragile thing in the world
세상에서 가장 깨지기 쉬운 것
It's humanity
인류다
soon
조만간
Your goodness will overcome.
당신의 선하심이 극복될 것입니다.
Because of what happened in the past
과거에 있었던 일들 때문에
I'll allow it this time.
이번에는 허락하겠습니다.
But if you use this dirty method
하지만 이런 더러운 방법을 사용한다면
Against the Hua family again
다시 Hua 가문에 반대
I will never show you mercy again.
나는 다시는 너희에게 자비를 베풀지 않을 것이다.
Debt securities brought in today
오늘 가져온 채무증권
Consider this a warning.
경고라고 생각하세요.
Hua Qian, what exactly do you want?
Hua Qian, 정확히 무엇을 원하시나요?
teach your nature
당신의 본성을 가르쳐라
Are you angry?
화가 났나요?
then
그렇다면
Think carefully before doing anything.
어떤 일을 하기 전에 신중하게 생각하십시오.
if you did something wrong
당신이 뭔가 잘못한 경우
You will be caught.
당신은 잡힐 것입니다.
one more
하나 더
I already confessed to Jong Ye-ran.
나는 이미 종예란에게 고백했다.
I disguised myself as you
내가 너로 변장했다고
I sent Zhong Yue Lan back to you.
나는 Zhong Yue Lan을 당신에게 돌려 보냈습니다.
I don't owe you anything anymore.
나는 더 이상 당신에게 빚진 것이 없습니다.
Give it back to me?
나한테 돌려줘?
Qianzi should have taken the divorce papers.
Qianzi는 이혼 서류를 가져갔어야 했어요.
I went to give it to Zhong Ye Lan.
나는 그것을 Zhong Ye Lan에게 주러 갔다.
From now on, your inner self and emotions
이제부터 당신의 내면 과 감정은
You can handle it yourself.
스스로 처리할 수 있습니다.
I will never get involved again.
나는 다시는 관여하지 않을 것이다.
Do you want a divorce?
이혼을 원하시나요?
yes
예
Don't get me involved.
나를 개입시키지 마십시오.
And it's a matter between you and Zhong Ye-ran.
그리고 당신과 종예란의 문제입니다.
Madame Chao
마담 차오
Where have you been?
어디 있었어?
Go and sort out your old problems.
가서 오래된 문제를 정리하세요.
What are you doing here?
여기서 뭐하는거야?
Qianzi explained. Did I not hear you clearly?
Qianzi는 설명했다. 내가 당신의 말을 명확하게 듣지 못했습니까?
What does it mean?
무슨 뜻이에요?
When leaving the head family residence
종가 저택을 떠날 때
Everyone will be happy.
모두가 행복할 것입니다.
That's nice, right?
그거 좋은데, 그렇지?
I thought you were going back to the painter's mansion.
당신은 화가 저택으로 돌아가는 줄 알았습니다.
Is that okay?
그거 괜찮아?
What does it mean?
무슨 뜻이에요?
Smiling Hua couldn't even protect himself.
웃고 있는 Hua는 자신도 보호할 수 없었습니다.
You are just a woman.
당신은 단지 여자입니다.
The Hwa family will protect you. How long can I receive it?
화가족이 당신을 지켜드립니다. 언제까지 받을 수 있나요?
Teacher, what does this mean?
선생님, 이게 무슨 뜻이에요?
Are you not going to say anything?
아무 말도 하지 않을 건가요?
So let me guess.
그럼 추측해 보겠습니다.
What you mean is
네 말 뜻은
You will help Mu Yao reverse his decision.
당신은 Mu Yao가 결정을 뒤집을 수 있도록 도와줄 것입니다.
Because I feel sorry for you
불쌍해서
So he allowed me to stay at the head house.
그래서 그는 나에게 종가대저택에 머물도록 허락해 주었습니다.
I won't get involved.
나는 관여하지 않을 것이다.
With the fall of the Fahrenheit family
화씨 가문의 몰락과 함께
then
그렇다면
Sir, you don't have to worry at all.
선생님, 전혀 걱정하지 않으셔도 됩니다.
You saved my life.
당신은 내 생명을 구했습니다.
I can't ignore you.
나는 당신을 무시할 수 없습니다.
So even if you want to go
그러니 가고 싶어도
Just wait a little longer.
조금만 더 기다리시면 됩니다.
I can protect you.
나는 당신을 보호할 수 있습니다.
Only if you were still in the Zhong Family Mansion.
아직 Zhong Family Mansion에 있었던 경우에만 가능합니다.
I accidentally saved your life.
내가 실수로 당신의 생명을 구했습니다.
If we go back to that incident
다시 그 사건으로 돌아가면
I will definitely remain silent and do nothing.
나는 반드시 침묵하고 아무것도 하지 않을 것이다.
You don't have to take it to heart.
마음에 새길 필요는 없습니다.
Please think of me as a reward.
나를 보상이라고 생각해주세요.
mistake made
저지른 실수
You and I don't owe each other anything.
당신과 나는 서로에게 빚진 것이 없습니다.
I don't need you.
난 당신이 필요하지 않습니다.
I can protect myself.
나는 나 자신을 보호할 수 있다.
Can you protect yourself?
당신은 자신을 보호할 수 있나요?
how?
어떻게?
You will protect yourself.
당신은 자신을 보호할 것입니다.
Like I did by creating a slanderous scene ?
비방하는 장면을 연출하여 내가 그랬던 것처럼요?
Who will we do the scene with? What does this have to do with you?
누구와 함께 장면을 만들까요? 이것이 당신과 무슨 관련이 있나요?
I am kind enough to ask for a divorce.
나는 이혼을 요청할만큼 친절합니다.
So that you and Mu Yao can be together.
당신과 Mu Yao가 함께 할 수 있도록.
Why should you be angry with me?
왜 나에게 화를 내야합니까?
Are you kind enough?
당신은 충분히 친절합니까?
Not at all, Hua Qian.
전혀 그렇지 않아요, Hua Qian.
You always think about yourself.
당신은 항상 자신에 대해 생각합니다.
- I... - You said you liked me.
- 난... - 나를 좋아한다고 했잖아.
So he disguised himself as Mu Yao.
그래서 그는 자신을 Mu Yao로 변장했습니다.
Then you want to marry me.
그럼 당신은 나와 결혼하고 싶어합니다.
So they poisoned me.
그래서 그들은 나를 독살했습니다.
Even when you took the arrow for me
네가 나를 위해 화살을 가져갔을 때도
You are just looking for excuses.
당신은 단지 변명을 찾고 있습니다.
to absolve myself
나 자신을 면죄하기 위해
That's enough for now
지금은 충분해요
You want a divorce.
당신은 이혼을 원합니다.
And left the head family residence.
그리고 종가 저택을 떠났다
You went to see the princess.
당신은 공주를 만나러 갔습니다.
So he ordered, Mu Yao, marry me.
그래서 그는 명령했다 무야오, 나랑 결혼해.
And forced me to choose
그리고 나에게 선택을 강요했다
this one
이 하나
They're really good at finding ways to avoid problems.
문제를 피하는 방법을 찾는 데 정말 능숙합니다.
You can always find a way to avoid problems.
문제를 피할 수 있는 방법은 언제든지 찾을 수 있습니다.
And you did that...
그리고 당신은 그렇게 했어요 ...
By manipulating everyone around him.
주변의 모든 사람을 조종함으로써.
- You... - What?
- 당신은... - 뭐?
You want to say that I am ungrateful and inhuman .
당신 은 내가 배은망덕하고 비인간적 이라고 말하고 싶습니다 .
And that's low, right?
그리고 그것은 낮습니다, 그렇죠?
Jong Ye-ran, you are ungrateful.
종예란, 당신은 배은망덕해요.
They are more corrupt than beasts.
짐승보다 더 타락했습니다.
How can you say that about yourself, my lord?
어떻게 자신에 대해 그렇게 말할 수 있습니까, 주인님?
Even now, I'm still pretending like that.
지금도 나는 그런 척을 하고 있다.
About divorce...
이혼에 대해서...
There is no way you will succeed.
당신이 성공할 방법은 없습니다.
government
정부
Looks like Master I will be very angry.
스승님 같네요 나는 매우 화를 낼 것입니다.
I've never seen it. He had never been this angry before.
나는 그것을 본 적이 없습니다. 그는 이전에 이렇게 화를 낸 적이 없었습니다.
I was careless.
나는 부주의했다.
I want to take action quickly.
빨리 조치를 취하고 싶습니다.
And did not take into account his dignity
그리고 그의 존엄성을 고려하지 않았습니다
I shouldn't have provoked him like this.
나는 그를 이렇게 자극하지 말았어야 했다.
I think I may have provoked it. give him what he wants
제가 자극을 했을 수도 있을 것 같아요. 그가 원하는 것을 그에게 줘
I resist more than before
전보다 더 저항해
That means he didn't go out that night.
그 말은 그 사람이 그날 밤에 나가지 않았다는 뜻이에요.
But did you secretly hear what I said?
그런데 내가 말하는 것을 몰래 들었나요?
So what should we do?
그럼 우리는 어떻게 해야 할까요?
are you okay.
괜찮아요.
Let's go to the head garden tomorrow.
내일은 종가 정원으로 가자.
"Extra Scenes"
"추가 장면"
What a waste.
정말 낭비입니다.
underfoot
발 밑에
Mistress's maids and guards
여주인의 하녀와 경비원
Follow the lady downstairs and ask her.
아래층 아줌마를 따라가서 물어보세요.
Let's go with that.
그걸로 가자.
Accept it.
그것을 받아들이십시오.
a few more days
며칠 더
Please tell the tailor to come see me.
재단사에게 나를 보러 오라고 전해주세요.
Accept it.
그것을 받아들이십시오.